Jaehyeok Shin

Email: shinjaehyeok@cmu.edu

Web: https://www.stat.cmu.edu/~jaehyeos/



RESEARCH SUMMARY

My research interest lies in understanding the sequential and adaptive nature of data analysis. I study how commonly used statistical inference procedures behave under the presence of an analyst's data-dependent choices. My current projects focus on designing and analyzing nonasymptotic sequential testings and online change-point detection procedures.

During the Ph.D., my thesis's focus was to qualitatively and quantitatively measure the selection bias caused by different sorts of human interventions in settings of adaptive experimentation like multi-armed bandits, advised by Aaditya Ramdas and Alessandro Rinaldo. I have also worked extensively with Larry Wasserman to understand the geometrical and topological structure of data-generating processes.

ACADEMIC APPOINTMENT

July 2020 - Postdoctoral Researcher,

Present Carnegie Mellon University, Department of Statistics

December 2013 - Statistical Consultant - Part Time,
December 2014 SNU Statistical Research Institute

EDUCATION

May 2020 Ph.D. in Statistics, Carnegie Mellon University

February 2015 M.S. in Statistics, Seoul National University

February 2013 B.S. in Mathematical Sciences, Seoul National University

PUBLICATIONS

2020 On conditional versus marginal bias in multi-armed bandits
J. Shin, A. Ramdas, A. Rinaldo
Thirty-seventh International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2020)

2020 Homotopy Reconstruction via the Cech Complex and the Rips Complex J. Kim, J. Shin, F. Chazal, A. Rinaldo, L. Wasserman Symposium on Computational Geometry (SoCG 2020)

2019 Are sample means in multi-armed bandits positively or negatively biased? J. Shin, A. Ramdas, A. Rinaldo Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS 2019, Spotlight)

Uniform Convergence Rate of the Kernel Density Estimator Adaptive to Intrinsic Dimension. J. Kim, J. Shin, A. Rinaldo, L. Wasserman

Thirty-sixth International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2019)

PREPRINTS

(arXiv) On the bias, risk and consistency of sample means in multi-armed bandits

J. Shin, A. Ramdas, A. Rinaldo Submitted to Sequential Analysis

(arXiv) Predictive clustering

J. Shin, A. Rinaldo, L. Wasserman
Submitted to Electronic Journal of Statistics

PRESENTATIONS

2020 On conditional versus marginal bias in multi-armed bandits (ICML 2020)

- 2019 Are sample means in multi-armed bandits positively or negatively biased? (NeurIPS 2019, Spotlight)
- 2018 Persistent homology of KDE filtration on Rips complex (SIAM-SEAS 2018)
- 2017 Persistent homology of KDE filtration on Rips complex (NIPS 2017 Workshop)

PEER REVIEW SERVICE

Neural Information Processing Systems (2020) Conference on Algorithmic Learning Theory (2020) Conference on Learning Theory (2019)

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2019 Teaching Assistant, Carnegie Mellon University

- Advanced Statistical Theory I, Spring 2019
- Advanced Statistical Theory, Fall 2018
- Advanced Methods for Data Analysis, Spring 2018
- Modern Regression, Fall 2017
- Special Topics: Data Mining, Spring 2017
- Modern Regression, Fall 2016
- Advanced Methods for Data Analysis, Spring 2016
- Introduction to Probability Theory, Fall 2015

2013 - 2014 Teaching Assistant, Seoul National University

- Statistics, Fall 2014
- Mathematical Statistics 2, Fall 2013
- Statistics, Spring 2013

Fall 2014 Academic Seminars, Seoul National University

- Organized lab seminars on deep learning
- Lectured a seminar on stacked auto-encoder and its simulation results

2014 Statistical Consulting, SNU Statistical Research Institute

- Analyzed risk factors for failure of cataract surgery in dogs
- Develop a statistical model to predict future water pipe ruptures in Seoul

Spring 2011 Undergraduate Tutor, Seoul National University

- Tutored first-year overseas Korean students
- Taught elementary calculus class twice a week

HONORS AND AWARDS

Spring 2014	Academic Excellence Prize, Seoul National University
2011 - 2012	National Scholarship For Science and Engineering
2007 - 2008	National Scholarship For Science and Engineering

COMMUNITY SERVICE

2016-Present	Served as a teacher of church youth group
2011	Served as a SNU Christian students union manager
2009 - 2010	Served as a military police in Korea army